There’s no place like home.
金窝银窝不如自家草窝。
It’s the place where we’re surrounded by our possessions and creature comforts.
家是被我们的私人物品和舒适便利设施环绕的地方。
We purchase things to give our homes a personal touch and create a certain ambience.
我们会购置物件来为家增添专属韵味，营造特定氛围。
And one thing we’re buying more of is houseplants.
而现在我们买得越来越多的一样东西，就是室内植物。
But are these ‘living’ additions to our homes good for us and the environment?
但这些为家增添生机的“活物”，对我们和环境真的有益吗？
Houseplants, also known as pot plants, have Instagram-friendly appeal; add a natural touch and they have the ability to brighten up a room on a budget.
室内植物也叫盆栽，自带适合社交平台展示的颜值；它们能为空间增添自然气息，还能让你低成本提亮整个房间。
The Royal Horticultural Society found that nearly 72% of adults in the UK had a houseplant in their home, with this figure rising to 80% of 16-24 year olds.
英国皇家园艺学会发现，英国近72%的成年人家里都有室内盆栽，在16至24岁的人群中，这一比例更是高达80%。
A fifth of owners also said they use plants in the home to boost their health and well-being.
五分之一的盆栽主人表示，在家中摆放植物是为了改善身心健康。
And average sales last year were up on the previous year.
而且盆栽的年平均销量也比前一年有所上涨。
It seems millennials are driving the growth in the sales of houseplants.
推动室内盆栽销量增长的主力军，似乎是千禧一代。
According to research by The Economist, more young people are living in flats without a garden.
据《经济学人》的研究显示，越来越多的年轻人住在没有花园的公寓里。
24 year-old Daisy Hale told the BBC "being able to care for something but not having too much commitment - I guess that's a classic millennial line - is ideal for my lifestyle."
24岁的黛西·黑尔在接受BBC采访时说：“能照料一个小生命，又不用承担太多责任——我觉得这就是千禧一代的典型想法——这种方式特别契合我的生活节奏。”
From hanging baskets, to cacti and succulent ferns, the choice of vegetation is endless.
从垂吊花篮到仙人掌、多肉蕨类，可供选择的绿植种类数不胜数。
They are easy to care for, and there have been unproven claims that they improve the air quality in our home.
它们打理起来简单方便，还有说法称室内盆栽能改善居家空气质量，只是这一说法尚未得到证实。
But whatever their benefits, there are now concerns that they are bad for the environment.
但无论它们有什么功效，如今有人开始担忧盆栽对环境并不友好。
Alice Vincent, a journalist and author, told the BBC "this could rack up ‘plant miles’".
记者兼作家爱丽丝·文森特告诉BBC：“这可能会产生大量的‘植物里程’。”
But botanist and BBC presenter James Wong argues that home delivery has less of an environmental impact than multiple trips to the garden centre in a car.
但植物学家、BBC主持人詹姆斯·王却认为，盆栽送货上门，比人们开车多次往返园艺中心更环保。
Although he’s not too concerned about the environmental impact, others are worried about the plastic pots they are in and the type of peat that some of them are grown in.
尽管他对盆栽的环境影响并不太在意，但其他人仍在担忧盆栽的塑料花盆，以及部分盆栽生长所依赖的泥炭。
However, a sustainable approach to buying them may be the best way forward if we want to introduce some natural greenery into our homes.
不过，如果我们想给家里增添一抹自然绿意，采用不破坏环境的的购买方式或许才是最佳出路。